<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
	<channel>
		<title>Max Briggs</title>
		<link>https://maxbriggs.org/</link>
		<description>Computer science, linguistics, journalism and my life. Mostly the latter.</description>
		<item>
			<title>Coronavirus Travel Day</title>
			<link>https://maxbriggs.org/blog/2020-03-09-coronavirus-travel.html</link>
			<guid>5dd21fd4-bb23-43b1-b41b-66893428911f</guid>
			<description>So as of Friday, the big three universities in Seattle have moved classes online...</description>
			<content:encoded>
			<p>So as of Friday, the big three universities in Seattle have moved classes online for the remainder of the quarter due to concerns over the coronavirus. With nothing keeping us here physically, a lot of students are leaving on their spring break trips early, myself included.</p>
			<p>I moved up my flight home from the day of my last final to Sunday yesterday. I did just get two weeks worth of food on Thursday, but three weeks of homecooked meals should make up for that.</p>
			<p>The anecdotes are true; the airports are much less crowded, though the flight that I was on was full. A few people were wearing masks, but the atmosphere was mostly relaxed. My one complaint is that because fewer people are in the airport, TSA was much less lenient when it came to what they were letting through.</p>
			</content:encoded>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Fall Quarter Wrap-up</title>
			<link>https://maxbriggs.org/blog/2019-12-07-fall_quarter_wrap-up.html</link>
			<guid>9e954fff-a0bc-4585-8cc9-42dfb87080da</guid>
			<description>Fall quarter kicked my ass...</description>
			<content:encoded>
                        <p>Fall quarter kicked my ass. Classes were hard and it has been an adjustment working at the Falcon.</p>
                        <p>The Falcon has been a good experience though. The editor staff that has been put together is really great. Everyone is good at their jobs and we are only getting better</p>
                        <p>The staff is great as well. We put out some really good news pieces like <a href="https://thefalcon.online/6182/news/food-insecurity-hits-close-to-home/">this one about food insecurity</a> and <a href="https://thefalcon.online/6034/opinions/no-human-being-is-illegal/">this op-ed about how we need to change our language around immigration</a>. Multimedia has put out a few videos as well, though not as many as I had hoped. That is what we will be focusing more on in the coming quarters.</p>
                        <p>Academically, I've struggled more this quarter than I have in the past. I think that it's because I have less unstructured time; it takes some forethought to get homework done when you are busy four nights a week.</p>
                        <p>Overall, I leave this quarter thoroughly exhausted, glad and looking forward to what comes ahead.</p>
			</content:encoded>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A Review of Vintage Hitchcock</title>
			<link>https://maxbriggs.org/blog/2019-11-25-review_of_vintage_hitchcock.html</link>
			<guid>5d7ffa17-f686-4baf-8349-413e37afac13</guid>
			<description>My brother's play was pretty good...</description>
			<content:encoded>
			<img style="float:right" src="resources/vhposter.jpg" alt="Vintage Hitchcock poster">
			<p>My brother's play was pretty good. Certainly not the best that his school has done, especially compared to their production of <em>The Laramie Project</em> last year. This year it was <em>Vintage Hitchcock: A Live Radio Play</em>.</p>
			<p>The premise is interesting: take three of Hitchcock's earlier movies, turn them into radio dramas and perform them in a radio studio on stage, including fake commercials and live Foley.</p>
			<p>The problems with this concept are that the story selection is not very strong and a radio play is not very interesting to watch.</p>
			<p>The first story <em>The Lodger</em> is a short and sweet story about a family that rents a room out to a man who bears strong resemblance to the serial killer "The Avenger". The second story is <em>Sabotage</em>, the longest of the three and the best. It tells the tale of a terrorist ring and the efforts of a Scotland Yard detective to stop them. The third, final and weakest of the bunch is <em>The 39 Steps</em>. It is a spy thriller following a man on the run for a murder he did not commit and his efforts to catch a ring of spies.</p>
			<p>The problem that arises with these stories is that there is a dissonance between the suspense that is created through the soundscape that the performers create and the inherent lack of suspense that comes from them speaking into a microphone in a radio station. When I closed my eyes and only listened, I was completely immersed. When I opened my eyes and watched, the play had the air of a dramatic script reading, not a production meant for public consumption.</p>
			<p>As far as the acting went, these kids can act. Their English accents, while not very authentic sounding, are consistent through the performance and are not distracting. Actors play multiple parts in each story and do well in giving a distinct voice to each of their characters. In one story a girl plays a 12 year old boy, an Eastern-European terrorist and the Lord Mayor of London, all of which are played with different and convincing voices.</p>
			<p>Sound design in this show features live sound effects created by the actors on stage. A large sheet of metal is rolled to imitate thunder. A small door is opened, closed, knocked on and locked to simulate the sound. A large sack is dropped as a body hits the ground. It is all blocked fantastically, sounds great and contributes well to the illusion that we are watching a radio station put on a radio play.</p>
			<p>Coming off of the heartwrenching masterpiece that was The Company's production of <em>The Laramie Project</em>, this show had less of an impact on me and will not stay with me as long as last year's show. For a high school production though, the acting is solid and I did not dread seeing it, which is a win in my book.</p>
			</content:encoded>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Airporting</title>
			<link>https://maxbriggs.org/blog/2019-11-22-airporting.html</link>
			<guid>bde3fe3e-d6c1-4769-91e1-31c02b8b102c</guid>
			<description>I'm on my way home for the weekend...</description>
			<content:encoded>
			<p>I'm on my way home for the weekend. While it's just a short jaunt from Seattle to Sacramento, flying makes me so fucking tired. I haven't even gotten on the plane and I'm ready for bed.</p>
			<content:encoded>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>First post</title>
			<link>https://maxbriggs.org/blog/2019-11-22-first.html</link>
			<guid>58a3c5dd-9d67-4d37-9f30-ec72c6545667</guid>
			<description>Hello, world!</description>
			<content:encoded>
			<p>Hello, world! This site started with the idea to make a completely static blog site / homepage. It took a little bit, but the blog is finally started.</p>
			<p>I'm Max, a third year comp sci and linguistics student at Seattle Pacific University. I'm also the Multimedia Editor for the school's newspaper <a href="https://thefalcon.online">The Falcon</a>.</p>
			<p>While my Twitter is mostly stream-of-consciousness bs, I'm hoping that this blog lends itself to longer, more thought out pieces of garbage.</p>
			</content:encoded>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
